DANIEL JAMES ROSE

PERSONAL DETAILS

NAMEDaniel RoseMOBILE+447742108486PLACE OF RESIDENCEHenley in ArdenEMAILim@danielro.seDRIVING LICENSEFull, cleanPORTFOLIOdanielro.se

An established web professional with over 6 years experience in the front-facing development and architecture of high volume websites, retaining a specialisation in e-commerce. Active in the web community as a published author. Proactively pursues refinements in a singular and collective workflow in order to to maximise efficiency and productiveness. Retains a considered approach in being at the forefront of the latest advancements in web technologies, which is ultimately driven by a strong personal passion. High attention to detail and pride in quality of code and deliverability of robust and intuitive user interfaces.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SITEPOINT Author. July 2014 - Present

Submit ideas to the editor, research agreed topics and compile useful external resources. Create demo's to support the article and complete a draft in markdown format for review. Implement and explore any suggestions made by the editor.

Interact with the community via the comments section.

TGGC Lead Front-end Developer. Aug 2014 - Present

Manage the team and offer support and guidance.

Evaluate each individual's skill set and development needs and delegate tasks accordingly.

Share and pool useful resources, encouraging the team to contribute.

Lead the recruitment process for team members.

Contribute to the content plan and strategy of the online side of the business.

Feedback new technologies, techniques and trends to the IT Director and Creative Lead.

Manage the workloads and priorities of the team.

Direct input into the design of digital media with the Creative team.

Plan and structure JavaScript namespace modules and SASS file structure.

Continuously improve the team's workflow by introducing new software, techniques and build processes.

TGGC Front-end Developer. April 2013 - Aug 2014

Code by hand HTML5 valid code, SASS and JavaScript/jQuery.

Working to strict deadlines and juggling an array of different tasks and projects.

Work in collaboration with back-end developers to ensure that the HTML generated is inline with the necessary page structure.

URL management and emphasising SEO, including structured data markup schema.

Cross device and browser testing.

Browser debugging and providing bug fixes, sometimes under intense pressure.

Liaise and work closely with the Creative team during development of their designs.

Email template development using best practice techniques.

BRD Support/Development Technician. 2010 - 2013

Responsible for design and front-end development of skins for an intranet workflow platform. Involved in daily scrum meetings.

Ensuring compatibility of client's browser of choice, in some cases Internet Explorer 6. Responsible for resolving front-end related support queries from clients.

DANIEL JAMES ROSE

CURRICULUM VITAE

RECOGNITIONS

<u>www.gemporia.com</u> The majority of my time is concentrated on the development of the core brand of the parent company 2013 - Present

<u>www.jewellerymaker.com</u> Oversaw and lead the build of the site which was subsequently bought in a multi million pound deal by Immediate Media 2015

<u>www.arthurivy.com</u> Sole front-end developer of showcase site for high end jewellery. 2014. <u>www.sitepoint.com/author/drose/</u> My Sitepoint author profile *2014*

danielro.se My personal portfolio and blog 2015 - Present

TECHNICAL SKILLS

OPERATING SYSTEMS

Well rounded knowledge of Windows, Mac, iOS and Android.

SOFTWARE

Atom	Chrome DevTools	Adobe Photoshop	Microsoft Office Suite
Sublime Text	Firebug	Sketch	MailChimp
Visual Studio	Fiddler	Trello	Mandrill
Grunt	SVN	Git	Emarsys

PROGRAMMING

HTML5	••••	CSS	••••	JavaScript	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$	Grunt	•••00
C#	••000	SASS	••••	jQuery	••••	Fabric.js	•••00
PHP	•0000	Compass	•••00	Knockout.js	•••00	Modernizr	•••00

^{*}The number of filled in dots indicates the skill level gained from past experience.

EDUCATION, QUALIFICATIONS & EXPERIENCES

TRAVELLING THE WORLD 2009
OXFORD BROOKES UNI 2005-08
WOODRUSH SIXTH FORM 2003-05
WOODRUSH HIGH SCHOOL 1998 - 2003

MICROSOFT SPECIALIST	Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3	2013
BSc HONS (2.1)	Modular Degree in Business Information Systems	2008
A-LEVEL	Bus. Studies, Information Sys, English Lit, Media	2005
GCSE	11.5 GCSE's grades A-C	2003

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

Fast promotion to lead front-end developer in current role
Selected by lecturer to develop a website for an external
business due to distinction in Web Design module
Travelling
Published author at www.sitepoint.com
Music fest Having an Academy contract with Birmingham City FC

OTHER INTERESTS

Gaming: PS4 and 3DS
Gadgets
Travelling
Music festivals
Playing and watching football

REFERENCES

Available upon request.